<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Karrin Huynh</title>
    <description>Bridging gaps with equity education</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2016 22:23:02 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2016 22:23:02 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.3.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Unit and Lesson Plans</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-multidisciplinary-lessons-that-i-create-incorporate-fundamental-learning-strategies-such-as-corporative-and-a-which-result-in-strong-student-engagement&quot;&gt;The multidisciplinary lessons that I create incorporate fundamental learning strategies such as corporative and a which result in strong student engagement.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to best support student success and engagement, I plan lessons that keep my students’ capabilities in mind while still maintaining high expectations. As a teacher candidate, I work to understand my students’ context in order to design lessons that directly affect them and their community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;global-action-to-citizen-action&quot;&gt;Global Action to Citizen Action&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Global Action to Citizen Action&lt;/em&gt; is a unit that I designed and delivered for a Grade 5/6 class. It began with introducing students to the United Nations and The United Nations Convention on the Rights of the Child, and understanding difference between rights and wants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next lesson couple lessons had students form a model UN, acting as countries that reflected the nationalities of the students. During their general assembly, students were dealing with the effects of a natural disaster and attempting to sort out different forms of aid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next couple lessons had students learning about different UN organizations, their mission statements and their plans of action. They then chose an issue that they felt passionate about, and created their own UN organization and connecting it how it might effect their local community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/UNpicture.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, students moved towards citizen action. We discussed issues that they and their community have been facing. The issues that the students brought up ranged from the lack of technology in their school to the negatives effects of the current revitalization of their neighbourhood. Students wrote letters to the school superintendent and city councillors to expression their concern and their plan for action to work cooperatively with them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/citizenactionletters.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;our-planets-our-universe&quot;&gt;Our Planets, Our Universe&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the same practicum placement, I planned a dynamic space unit which included research and student presentations, hands on inquiry, an astronomer as a guest speaker and a field trip to the University of Toronto’s planetarium.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While facilitating a hands inquiry activity, students were able to see and understand why certain places on the Earth experience different seasons depending on the Earth’s tilt during it’s revolution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to provide a more in depth unit on astronomy, I organized to have a University of Toronto Astronomer come into to the classroom to talk about the planets beyond our solar system. He also spoke about the amazing contributions that Islamic astronomers made to the field of astronomy. The Muslim students found this especially interesting and empowering.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2015 21:55:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2015/07/11/demo-post.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2015/07/11/demo-post.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Supporting STEM in Schools</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;my-commitment-to-student-learning-is-also-evident-through-the-extracurricular-stem-focused-clubs-i-have-introduced-and-led&quot;&gt;My commitment to student learning is also evident through the extracurricular STEM focused clubs I have introduced and led.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My math and phys-ed club for Grade 5/6 students had students working collaboratively on math problems through physical activity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My computer coding club, for grade 2 students, teaches coding concepts through reasoning and collaborative work. Using the iPad app Scratch Jr. and Code.org’s Hour of Code, students engage in play based and inquiry based problem solving activities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using Scratch Jr., students program their own interactive stories. The learning goals for the club was to learn how to make predictions, create and carry out rules (simple algorithms), test, and revise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/scratchjr.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using code.org’s Hour of Code, students are continuing to be introduced to the foundations of programming, but within the context of popular culture such as Minecraft, Frozen and Star Wars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/hourofcode.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2015 21:54:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2015/07/11/color-choices.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2015/07/11/color-choices.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My Storybook</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;recipient-of-the-american-association-of-school-librarians-best-website-for-teaching-and-learning-for-2015-mystorybookhttpwwwmystorybookcom-is-a-educational-technology-website-where-students-can-write-illustrate-and-publish-their-own-online-storybooks&quot;&gt;Recipient of the American Association of School Librarians’ “Best Website for Teaching and Learning” for 2015, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mystorybook.com&quot;&gt;MyStorybook&lt;/a&gt; is a educational technology website where students can write, illustrate and publish their own online storybooks.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has been built for students and teachers to work together on exercising students’ literacy and digital literacy skills. We currently have over 150,000 educators and student users worldwide who have created over 250,000 books.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/kids.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;integrating-my-storybook-into-the-classroom&quot;&gt;Integrating My Storybook into the classroom&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our tool provides a great opportunity for differentiated learning. As educator, we teach students both content (teaching students about a topic) as well as process (teaching students how to do something).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you’re teaching students about a concept, such as the water cycle or photosynthesis,
educators can offer a choice for how students will demonstrate learning.  Once of these choices can be using MyStorybook to create their own online story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/timmy.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Timmy uses mental math, mixes both literacy and mathematics, where a student is expressing important mathematics strategies and relationships but through the art of storytelling. 
 When teaching students how to master a process, for example how to write from another point of view other than their own, students can use MyStorybook and choose what the content of what their dialog might be about. This provides the potential to have many students who are all practicing the skill of point of view, but they are all writing about a topic that interests them, which will get students more engaged with the activity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/boyadoll.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MyStorybook has also been used as a platform to share and interact with important social issues.  If you give a boy a doll, is a boy who prefers to play with dolls and a girl who prefers to play with footballs. The main message of this book is that no matter what your gender is, there should not be specific toys you’re expected to play with, there shouldn’t be specific colours that you need to prefer over others. So this book is about battling those gender stereotypes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-importance-of-being-published&quot;&gt;The importance of being published&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is definitely something to be said about being published! Especially for students. 
We all know that having a real audience make a big difference. Usually classroom assignments
are only seen by teachers and maybe their peers. This opportunity to have students publish
their work to our community of young authors and whoever they’d like to send their story to will
hopefully be a really exciting incentive for students to engage in literacy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/publish.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2015 09:50:39 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2015/07/11/welcome-to-jekyll.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2015/07/11/welcome-to-jekyll.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
